a little bit sheepishly, actually, about this idea that maybe we could use these patterns and shapes to produce a wetsuit to try and mitigate the risk of shark attack, and fortunately, he thought that was a good idea. So what ensued is a collaborative bit of research supported by the West Australian State Government. And we did three key things. The first is that we mapped the characteristics, the physical characteristics of the eyes of the three main predatory sharks, so the great white, tiger and bull shark. We did that genetically and we did that anatomically. The next thing we did was to understand, using complex computer modeling, what that eye can see at different depths, distances, light conditions, and water clarity in the ocean. And from there, we were able to pinpoint two key characteristics: what patterns and shapes would present the wearer as hidden or hard to make out in the water, cryptic, and what patterns and shapes might provide the greatest contrast but provide the greatest breakup of profile so that that person wasn't confused for shark prey or shark food. The next thing we needed to do was to convert this into wetsuits that people might actually wear, and to that end, I invited Ray Smith, a surfer, industrial designer, wetsuit designer, and in fact the guy that designed the original Quiksilver logo, to come over and sit with the science team and interpret that science into aesthetic wetsuits that people might actually wear. And here's an example of one of the first drawings. So this is what I call a "don't eat me" wetsuit. So this takes that banding idea, takes that banding idea, it's highly visible, provides a highly disruptive profile, and is intended to prevent the shark from considering that you would be ordinary food, and potentially even create confusion for the shark. And this one's configured to go with a surfboard. You can see that dark, opaque panel on the front, and it's particularly better for the surface, where being backlit and providing a silhouette is problematic. Second iteration is the cryptic wetsuit, or the one which attempts to hide the wearer in the water column. There are three panels on this suit,
algo tímidamente, sobre esta idea de usar patrones y formas para hacer un traje que redujera el riesgo de ataques, y pensó que era una buena idea. Lo siguiente fue una investigación conjunta con apoyo del Gobierno del oeste de Australia. Entonces hicimos 3 cosas clave. La primera fue mapear las características físicas de los ojos de los principales tiburones predadores, o sea, el tiburón blanco, el tigre y el toro. Lo hicimos genéticamente y también anatómicamente. Lo siguiente fue entender con un modelado informático, qué puede ver ese ojo según la profundidad, distancia, condiciones de luz, y claridad del agua del océano. Así, identificamos dos características clave: qué patrones y formas llevaría el usuario para ocultarse o ser difícil de divisar en el agua, y cuáles podrían aportar el mayor contraste y a la vez la mayor desintegración del perfil para que no sea confundida con una presa o alimento de tiburón. Lo siguiente fue convertir esto en trajes de baño que la gente se pusiera, y para eso invitamos a Ray Smith, surfista, diseñador industrial y de trajes de baño, diseñó el logo original de Quiksilver, para que se reuniera con el equipo científico y usara esa ciencia en un traje estético que la gente llevara puesto. Este es uno de los primeros modelos. Es lo que llamo un traje "no me comas". Tiene esa idea de las bandas, (Risas) tiene las bandas, muy visibles, son perturbadoras, y se diseñó para que el tiburón no nos considere comida corriente, e incluso para confundir al tiburón. Y este está diseñado para usar con una tabla de surf, con esa parte oscura del frente, y es mejor sobre todo para la superficie. donde la retroilimunación y mostrar una silueta es un problema. El segundo modelo es el traje de camuflaje, que oculta al portador en la columna de agua. Este traje tiene 3 paneles,
and in any given conditions, one or more of those panels will match the reflective spectra of the water so as to disappear fully or partially, leaving the last panel or panels to create a disruptive profile in the water column. And this one's particularly well-suited to the dive configuration, so when you're deeper under the water. So we knew that we had some really solid science here. We knew, if you wanted to stand out, you needed to look stripy, and we knew if you wanted to be cryptic, you needed to look like this. But the acid test is always going to be, how would sharks really behave in the context of these patterns and shapes. And testing to simulate a person in a wetsuit in the water with a predatory shark in a natural environment is actually a lot harder than you might think. (Laughter) So we have to bait the rig, because we need to get the statistical number of samples through to get the scientific evidence, and by baiting the rig, we're obviously changing shark behavior. We can't put humans in the water. We're ethically precluded from even using humanoid shapes and baiting them up in the water. But nevertheless, we started the testing process in January of this year, initially with tiger sharks and subsequently with great white sharks. The way we did that was to get a perforated drum which is full of bait, wrap it in a neoprene skin, and then run two stereo underwater cameras to watch how the shark actually engages with that rig. And because we use stereo, we can capture all the statistics on how big the shark is, what angle it comes in at, how quickly it leaves, and what its behavior is in an empirical rather than a subjective way. Because we needed to preserve the scientific method, we ran a control rig which was a black neoprene rig just like a normal black wetsuit against the, what we call, SAMS technology rig. And the results were not just exciting, but very encouraging, and today I would like to just give you a snapshot of two of those engagements. So here we've got a four-meter tiger shark engaging the black control rig, which it had encountered about a minute and a half before. Now that exact same shark had engaged, or encountered this SAMS rig, which is the Elude SAMS rig, about eight minutes before, and spent six minutes circling it, hunting for it, looking for what it could smell and sense but not see, and this was the final engagement. Great white sharks are more confident than the tigers, and here you see great white shark engaging a control rig, so a black neoprene wetsuit, and going straight to the bottom, coming up and engaging. In contrast to the SAMS technology rig, this is the banded one, where it's more tactile, it's more investigative, it's more apprehensive, and shows a reluctance to come straight in and go. (Applause) So, it's important for us that all the testing is done independently, and the University of W.A. is doing the testing. It'll be an ongoing process. It's subject to peer review and subject to publication. It's so important that this concept is led with the science. From the perspective of Shark Attack Mitigation Systems, we're a biotechnology licensing company, so we don't make wetsuits ourselves. We'll license others to do that. But I thought you might be interested in seeing what SAMS technology looks like embedded in a wetsuit, and to that end, for the first time, live, worldwide -- (Laughter) — I can show you what biological adaptation, science and design looks like in real life. So I can welcome Sam, the surfer, from this side. Where are you, Sam? (Applause) And Eduardo. Cheers, mate. Cheers. Thanks, gentlemen. (Applause) So what have we done here? Well, to my mind, rather than take a blank sheet and use science as a tool for invention, we've paid attention to the biological evidence, we've put importance to the human anecdotal evidence, and we've used science as a tool for translation, translation of something that was already there into something that we can use for the benefit of mankind. And it strikes me that this idea of science as a tool for translation rather than invention is one that we can apply much more widely than this in the pursuit of innovation. After all, did the Wright brothers discover manned flight, or did they observe the biological fact of flight and translate that mechanically, replicate it in a way that humans could use? As for the humble wetsuit, who knows what oceanwear will look like in two years' time, in five years' time or in 50 years' time, but with this new thinking, I'm guessing there's a fair chance it won't be pure black. Thank you. (Applause)
para distintas condiciones. Uno o más de ellos serán como los espectros de reflexión para desaparecer total o parcialmente, dejando al resto para crear un perfil perturbador en la columna. Este es especialmente adecuado para el buceo o sea, a mayor profundidad. Supimos que aquí teníamos ciencia muy sólida. Sabíamos que para destacar había que llevar rayas, y que si para camuflarse tenía que ir así. La prueba de fuego es qué hacen los tiburones ante estos patrones y formas. Las pruebas de personas en trajes de baño en el agua con tiburones en un entorno natural es más difícil de lo que parece. (Risas) Así que tenemos que usar un cebo, para obtener el número de muestras para conseguir pruebas científicas, y con el cebo cambiamos el comportamiento del tiburón. No vamos a usar gente, la ética nos impide incluso usar figuras humanoides como cebo en el agua. Aun así, empezamos el proceso de prueba en enero de este año, primero con tiburones tigre y después con tiburones blancos. Lo hicimos con un tambor perforado lleno de cebo, revestido de neopreno, y luego pusimos dos cámaras estéreo subacuáticas para ver qué hacía el tiburón con el cebo. Y como usamos estéreo podemos saber cuál es el tamaño del tiburón, ángulo de entrada, velocidad de salida, y su comportamiento, de manera empírica más que subjetiva. Como debíamos preservar el método científico, teníamos un cebo de control que era de neopreno negro como el de un traje negro normal contra lo que llamamos cebo de tecnología SAMS. Los resultados no solo fueron apasionantes, sino muy alentadores. Hoy les mostraré dos de esos resultados alentadores. Este es un tiburón tigre de 4 metros interactuando con el cebo negro de control que había encontrado un minuto y medio antes. El mismo tiburón había interactuado, encontrado este cebo SAMS, el cebo Elude SAMS, unos ocho minutos antes, y pasó seis dando vueltas, para cazarlo, buscando lo que podía olfatear pero no ver y esta es la última interacción. Los blancos tienen más seguridad que los tigres, y aquí está el tiburón blanco con el cebo de control, el de neopreno negro, yendo directo hacia abajo, subiendo e interactuando. En contraste con el cebo de tecnología SAMS, este tiene rayas, es más táctil, investiga más, es más ansioso y es reticente a venir directamente e irse. (Aplausos) Es importante que las pruebas se hagan de forma independiente, la UWA se encarga de ellas. Será un proceso continuo, sujeto a revisión por pares y a publicación. Es importante que este concepto se guíe por la ciencia. Desde la perspectiva de Mitigación de Ataques, llevamos licencias de biotecnología, y como no hacemos trajes de baño, damos las licencias y los hacen otros. Es interesante ver cómo es la tecnología SAMS integrada en un traje y, para eso, por primera vez, en directo, para el mundo, (Risas) puedo mostrar cómo es la adaptación biológica la ciencia y el diseño en la vida real. Demos la bienvenida a Sam, el surfista, por aquí, ¿dónde estás, Sam? (Aplausos) Y a Eduardo. Hola, amigo. Hola. Gracias, señores. (Aplausos) ¿Qué hemos hecho aquí? Bueno, para mí, en vez de tomar una hoja en blanco y usar la ciencia como herramienta de invención, hemos prestado atención a las pruebas biológicas, le hemos dado importancia a la prueba anecdótica humana, y hemos usado la ciencia como herramienta de traducción, traducción de algo que ya estaba allí en algo que podemos usar en beneficio de la humanidad. Pienso que esta idea de la ciencia como herramienta de traducción más que de invención puede aplicarse de forma más amplia que esta en la búsqueda de la innovación. Después de todo, los hermanos Wright, ¿descubrieron el vuelo tripulado u observaron el hecho biológico de volar y tradujeron eso mecánicamente, lo replicaron, para que los humanos pudiéramos usarlo? Y el traje de neopreno, quién sabe cómo será su aspecto de aquí a dos, cinco o 50 años, pero con este nuevo pensamiento, supongo que es poco probable que sea meramente negro. Gracias. (Aplausos)